Contact

Coral Bloack , Flat 8A, Opaline Apartments, Navallur, 9700531000 (Home) nagakiran224@outlook.com

www.linkedin.com/in/nagakiran224 (LinkedIn) stackoverflow.com/users/8208006/

Top Skills

Machine Learning Microsoft Azure Analytical Skills

naga-kiran (Personal)

Certifications

Machine Learning
Deep learning Specialization
Coursera
Neural Networks and Deep Learning

Convolutional Neural Networks

Naga Kiran

Machine Learning | NLP | Data Science | Ex-TCSer Chennai

Summary

Python Developer with more than 3 years of experience in Machine learning model building and research.

Descriptive analysis on customer problematic Data. Analyzing the insights associated with frequent occurrence problems in Engineering industries and providing proper Analytic solution with Machine learning and Deep learning models.

https://stackoverflow.com/users/8208006/naga-kiran

Experience

WABCO

Machine Learning Engineer March 2019 - Present (1 year 6 months)

Chennai Area, India

Building Predictive Maintenance models for WABCO sensitive machinery and replicating the sensor behaviour in Augmented Reality screen.

- NLP:
- Built a Voice authenticated re-trainable chatbot with Google BERT Question and answering model.
- Built Deep learning Object detection with Customized OCR engine to apply on Generic Text Extracting model from PDFs

Seguential Data

- Preprocessing and Extracting insights from raw sensors data.
- Implementing LSTM AutoEncoder differentiate modeling in Predicting the anomalous behavior of Machinery.

Tata Consultancy Services 2 years 8 months

System Engineer (Machine Learning Engineer) August 2017 - March 2019 (1 year 8 months)

Chennai Area, India

Projects:

- -- Failure detection of Cavity Pumps used in Oil well and Predicting Failure Cause
- -- Text Mining to retrieve required information from Text summary and Text Comparing with Similarity Algorithms.
- Descriptive analysis and understanding the time series data.
- Cleaning, formatting the data with specific Sequential preprocessing steps.
- Implementing and Fine tuning of LSTM deep learning model . Visualizing data using python libraries like Plotly, Bokeh.

Machine Learning Engineer - Trainee January 2017 - August 2017 (8 months)

Chennai Area, India

Project: Anomaly Detection of Failure Batteries with Semi supervised Deep learning Model using LSTM Auto Encoder and Decoder.

- Implementing Deep Learning algorithm from research paper using keras deep learning frame work.
- Static visualization Matplotlib, Seaborn and for interactive visualization Plotly, Bokeh.

PL/SQL Developer

August 2016 - December 2016 (5 months)

Chennai Area, India

Project: VODAPHONE_UK_EIGER_SUPPORT-OFF

- Writing effective, scalable code. Developing back-end components to improve responsiveness and overall performance.
- Task implementation in PL/SQL modules and pushing Code to application.
- Supporting application server and issue resolving.

TRANSMISSION CORPORATION OF ANDHRA PRADESH LIMITED

Junior Engineer Intern
May 2012 - November 2012 (7 months)

Vijayawada Area, India

- Evaluates electrical systems, products, components, and applications by designing and conducting research programs
- Applying knowledge of electricity and materials. Confirms system's and components' capabilities by designing testing methods; testing properties.
- Time to time response of Electrical scheduled operations

Education

VR SIDDHARTHA ENG COLLEGE VJW

Bachelor's degree, Electrical and Electronics Engineering · (2013 - 2016)